Finding Aid for F. Thomas Juster papers, 1960-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Writings
  - General
    - An Evaluation of the Recent Record in Short-Term Forecasting 1971 (Box 7)
    - Ex-Ante Household Savings Data: Some Preliminary Results 1971 (Box 7)
    - An Expectational View of Consumer Spending Prospects 1981 (Box 7)
    - An Experiment in Data Collection: Use of Financial Records 1977 (Box 7)
    - Exploring the Changing Nature of U.S. Stock Market Participation 1994-1999, 2004 (Box 7)
    - Factors Affecting Household Saving Behavior: An Introductory Analysis 1990 (Box 7)
    - "Fairness" and Social Policy 1984 (Box 7)
      (pages 11 and 12 missing)
    - Federal Policy on Statistics: An Academic View 1988 (Box 7)
    - The Fiscal Impact of General Revenue Sharing: A Summary Statement 1977 (Box 7)
    - A Framework for the Measurement of Economic and Social Performance 1973 (Box 7)
    - Goods, Time and Well-Being: The Joint Dependence Problem 1980 (Box 7)
    - Going Beyond a Current Income: A Preliminary Appraisal 1976 (Box 7)
      (from Albert Biderman and Thomas Drury Measuring Work Quality for Social Reporting)
    - Government Support of Economic Research: An Evaluation 1981 (Box 7)
    - Health and Functioning Measures from the Health and Retirement Survey 1993 (Box 7)
    - Household Capital Formation: Growth, Cyclical Behavior, and Financing 1897-1962, 1965 (Box 7)
    - The Impact of Consumer Attitudes and Behavior on the Economy 1984 (Box 8)
    - The Impact of Technological Change on Time Use and Household Production 1975 (Box 8)
    - Impacts of Changes in Methods and Technology on Social Science Research 1983 (Box 8)
    - Improving The Quality of Economic Data: Lessons from the HRS and AHEAD 1997 (Box 8)
    - Income and Wealth of Older American Households: Modeling Issues for Public Policy Analysis 1994 (Box 8)
    - Inflation and the Consumer 1972 (Box 8)
    - Inflation and Consumer Behavior: Changing Responses to Changing Perceptions 1981 (Box 8)
      (Nikkei Kyutsu Shimbun Commemorative Lecture, Tokyo)
    - Inflation and Consumer Saving Behavior 1977 (Box 8)
    - Inflation and Consumer Savings Behavior: Some Time-Series and Cross-Section Results 1975 (Box 8)
    - Inflation in the Decade of the 1980s, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Inflationary Expectations and Consumer Behavior 1979 (Box 8)
    - The Influence of Heterogeneity and Shocks on Modeling Saving Behavior undated (Box 8)
    - Integrating Stocks and Flows in Quality of Life Research 1983 (Box 8)
    - The Investment of Time by U.S. Households: An Initial View 1979 (Box 8)
    - It's Up to the Consumer Again 1977 (Box 8)
      (from Ward's Auto World)
    - Macroeconomic Insights from a Behavioral Perspective 1984 (Box 8)
    - On the Measurement of Economic and Social Performance 1970 (Box 8)
    - On the Measurement of Expectations, Uncertainty, and Preferences 1997 (Box 8)
    - The Measurement and Structure of Household Wealth 1998 (Box 8)
    - Methodological Developments in the Measurement of Economic Status 1996 (Box 8)
    - Methodology, Data Quality and Interpretation: Some Notes on Consumer Surveys 1976 (Box 8)
    - Microdata, Economic Research, and the Production of Economic Knowledge 1970 (Box 8)
    - Microdata Requirements and Public Policy Designs 1971 (Box 8)
    - Money, Goods and Time: Alternative Ways to Monitor Social Change 1979 (Box 8)
    - New Evidence on Altruism: A Study of TIAA-CREF Retirees 1992-1993 (Box 8)
    - A Note on Categorization of Wants and Indicators 1977 (Box 8)
    - A Note on Consumer Asset Formation in the United States 1966-1967 (Box 8)
    - A Note on Differences in Recent Consumer Survey Data 1978 (Box 8)
    - A Note on Distributed Lag Equations and Dummy Variables undated (Box 8)
    - A Note on the Measurement of Price Expectations 1978-1979 (Box 8)
    - A Note on Price Inflation and the Savings Rate 1972 (Box 8)
      (Brookings Conference on Economic Activity)
    - A Note on Prospective 1977 Tax Cuts and Consumer Spending, 1977 (Box 8)
    - A Note on Uncertainty, Expectations and Durable Goods Demand Models 1970 (Box 8)
    - Notes on "Whither Economics and the NSF Economics Program," undated (Box 8)
    - Odds Shifting Towards Recession 1978 (Box 8)
    - The Outlook for Consumer Spending in 1972 and Beyond, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Prediction and Consumer Buying Intentions 1960 (Box 8)
    - The Predictive Value of Consumers Union Spending-Intentions Data 1960 (Box 8)
    - Preference Parameters and Behavioral Heterogeneity: An Experimental Approach in the Health and Retirement Survey 1995 (Box 8)
    - Presentation and Analysis of Comparisons Between Records and Recall Data 1980 (Box 8)
    - Procedures for Correcting Problems in AHEAD 1993 Asset Data, 2004 (Box 8)
    - The Psychology of Inflation: Why is Inflation Bad? 1979 (Box 8)
    - The Racial Digital Divide Among Children: Closing or Widening at the Turn of the Decade 2004 (Box 8)
    - Recent Changes in Work Versus Nonwork Time: Conflicting Evidence 1993 (Box 8)
    - The Recovery Gathers Momentum 1976 (Box 8)
    - Research on Retirement Saving and Investment and Behavior undated (Box 8)
    - Rethinking Utility Theory 1985 (Box 8)
    - Retirement Security Simulation Study 1982 (Box 8)
    - The Role of Expectations in Economics 1981 (Box 8)
      (Prepared for Joint Economic Committee, U.S. Congress)
    - The Role of Microdata in the Production of Economic Knowledge 1984 (Box 8)
    - The Role of Panel Studies in Research on Economic Behavior 1987 (Box 8)
    - The Saving Behavior of American Families 1984-1989, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Savings Behavior, Uncertainty, and Price Expectations 1974 (Box 8)
    - Savings and Wealth: Then and Now 1997 (Box 8)
      (Presented at Conference on Health and Retirement, Amsterdam)
    - The Sensitivity of the Incidence of Poverty to Different Measures of Income: School-Aged Children and Families 1975 (Box 8)
    - Social Indicators and Social Accounts: Outlines of a Comprehensive System for Understanding Social and Economic Change undated (Box 8)
    - A Social Information System for the Analysis of Well-Being: Theory, Framework, Linkages, and Data Base 1979 (Box 8)
    - Social Science Research in a Conservative Society 1981 (Box 8)
    - Social Science Research in a Conservative Society: The Impact of the Reagan Budget Cuts 1982 (Box 8)
    - Social Security, Private Saving, and All That 1980 (Box 8)
    - Some Benefits and Costs of Going Beyond Current Income 1974 (Box 8)
    - Some Costs and Non-Money Benefits of Work 1975 (Box 8)
    - Some Experimental Results in Measuring Purchase Probability for Durables, and Some Tentative Explorations of Time-Series Demand Models 1967 (Box 8)
    - Some Interrelationships Among Expectational Variables and Durable Goods Purchases 1962 (Box 8)
    - Some Perspectives on the Study of Time Use undated (Box 8)
    - The State of U.S. Economic Statistics: Current and Prospective Quality, Policy Needs, and Resources 1988 (Box 8)
    - Survey Design and Data Quality: An Assortment of the Asset and Income Data in the HRS and AHEAD Surveys 2004 (Box 8)
    - A Tax Cut Might do Much for Saving 1981 (Box 8)
      (from Fortune Magazine)
    - Technological Change and Social Science Research 1984 (Box 8)
    - Time-Series Changes in Wealth Measurement for both HRS and AHEAD 2004 (Box 8)
    - Time Use: Diary and Direct Reports 2001 (Box 8)
    - Towards a Theory of Saving Behavior 1974 (Box 8)
    - Trends and Turbulence: Allocations and Dynamics of American Family Portfolios 1984-2001, 2003 (Box 8)
    - Uncertainty, Expectations, and Durable Goods Demand Models 1971 (Box 8)
    - The Underground Economy in the United States: A Time-Use Approach 1987 (Box 8)
    - The Use of Surveys for Policy Research 1974 (Box 8)
    - The Use of Surveys for Policy Research: A Research Allocation View 1973 (Box 8)
    - Use of U.S. Economic and Social Data for the Study of Income, Wealth, and Saving 1989 (Box 8)
    - Validity Procedures at the Survey Research Center undated (Box 8)
    - The Validity and Quality of Time-Use Estimates Obtained from Recall Diaries 1985 (Box 8)
    - Well-Being: Concepts and Measures 2000 (Box 8)
    - What do We Know About Saving Behavior? 1986 (Box 8)
    - What have We Learned from Surveys about Human Behavior? 1987 (Box 8)
  - ISR Working Papers
    - The Allocation of Time: Empirical Findings, Behavioral Models, and Problems of Measurement 1990 (Box 8)
    - Constraints and Complementaries in Time Use 1980 (Box 8)
    - Current and Prospective Financial Status of the Elderly Population 1981 (Box 9)
    - Empirical Findings, Behavioral Models, and Problems of Measurement 1990 (Box 9)
    - Goods, Satisfaction with Activities, and Well-Being: An Exploratory Analysis 1980 (Box 9)
    - Saving, Economic Growth and Economic Policy 1981 (Box 9)
    - Social Accounting and Social Indicators: a Framework for the Analysis of Well-Being 1979 (Box 9)
    - Survey Estimates of Wealth: An Assessment of Quality 1988 (Box 9)
    - The Theory and Measurement of Well-Being: A Suggested Framework for Accounting and Analysis 1980 (Box 9)